I'm McKenna Pope. I'm 14 years old,
انا ماكينا بوب وانا عمري 14 سنة
and when I was 13, I convinced
عندما كنت في 13 من عمري أقنعت
one of the largest toy companies,
واحدة من أكبر شركات الألعاب
toymakers, in the world, Hasbro,
وصانعوا الألعاب في العالم ،هاسبرو،
to change the way that they marketed
لتغيير الطريقة التي كانوا يسوقون بها
one of their most best-selling products.
واحدة من المنتجات الأكثر مبيعاً.
So allow me to tell you about it.
لذا اسمحوا لي أن اخبركم عن هذا الموضوع.
So I have a brother, Gavin.
حسنا ، لدى شقيق أسمه جافين.
When this whole shebang happened, he was four.
عندما حدث هذا الكوخ كله، كان في الرابعة من عمره.
He loved to cook.
كان يحب طهي الطعام.
He was always getting ingredients out of the fridge
كان دائم الحصول على المكونات من الثلاجة
and mixing them into these, needless to say,
وخلطهم معا وبالطبع لستم بحاجة لأخبركم
uneatable concoctions,
مخلوطات لا تُأكل
or making invisible macaroni and cheese.
أو المعكرونة الغير مرئية والجبن.
He wanted to be a chef really badly.
كان يريد بشدة ان يكون رئيس طهاة
And so what better gift for a kid who wanted to be a chef
و ما هي أفضل هدية لطفل يريد أن يكون رئيس طهاة
than an Easy-Bake Oven. Right?
من فرن خبز سهل. أليس كذلك؟
I mean, we all had those when we were little.
يعني جميعنا كان لدينا هذا عندما كنا صغار
And he wanted one so badly.
وأراد واحد بشدة.
But then he started to realize something.
ولكن بدأ يدرك أمر ما
In the commercials, and on the boxes for the Easy-Bake Ovens,
في الإعلانات التجارية، وفي صناديق أفران الخبز سهلة التحضير
Hasbro marketed them specifically to girls.
هاسبرو يسوقوهم خصيصا للفتيات.
And the way that they did this
والطريقة التي فعلوا بها هذا
was they would only feature girls on the boxes or in the commercials,
أنهم استخدموا الفتيات فقط على الصناديق أو في الإعلانات التجارية،
and there would be flowery prints all over the ovens
وكان هناك مطبوعات من الزهور في جميع أنحاء أفران
and it would be in bright pink and purple,
بلون وردي وقرمزي
very gender-specific colors to females, right?
ألوان مخصوصة للفتيات فقط ، أليس كذلك ؟
So it kind of was sending a message
وبالتالي كان نوع من ارسال رسالة
that only girls are supposed to cook; boys aren't.
أن الفتيات فقط من المفترض أن يطهو لا الفتيان.
And this discouraged my brother a lot.
وهذا سبب الإحباط لأخي كثيرا.
He thought that he wasn't supposed to want to be a chef,
حيث أعتقد أنه لم يكن من المفترض ألا يريد أن يكون طاهيا،
because that was something that girls did.
لأن ذلك كان شيئا تفعله البنات.
Girls cooked; boys didn't,
الفتيات تطهو لكن الفتيان لا يفعلوا ذلك
or so was the message that Hasbro was sending.
او هكذا كانت رسالة هاسبرو
And this got me thinking,
وهذا جعلني أفكر
God, I wish there was a way that I could change this,
يا ربي ... أود لو أن هناك وسيلة يمكنني بها تغيير ذلك
that could I have my voice heard by Hasbro
يمكنني بها توصيل صوتي لهاسبرو
so I could ask them and tell them
حيث يمكن أن أطلب منهم وأقول لهم
what they were doing wrong
ان ما يفعلوه كان خطأ
and ask them to change it.
ونطلب منهم تغييره.
And that got me thinking about a website
وهذا جعلني أفكر في موقع إلكتروني
that I had learned about a few months prior
وهذا ما تعلمته من بضعة شهور مضت
called Change.org.
يسمى Change.org.
Change.org is an online petition-sharing platform
Change.org منصة لمشاركة المواقع على الإنترنت
where you can create a petition and share it
حيث يمكنك إنشاء عريضة ومشاركتها
across all of these social media networks,
عبر كل من هذه الشبكات الاجتماعية وسائل الإعلام،
through Facebook, through Twitter,
من خلال فيس بوك، من خلال تويتر
through YouTube, through Reddit, through Tumblr,
من خلال موقع يوتيوب، من خلال ريديت، من خلال تمبلر،
through whatever you can think of.
من خلال كل ما يخطر علي بالك
And so I created a petition
وهكذا أنشئت عريضة
along with the YouTube video that I added to the petition
جنبا إلى جنب مع فيديو يوتيوب وأضفته إلي العريضة
basically asking Hasbro
يطلب من هاسبرو في الأساس
to change the way that they marketed it,
تغيير الطريقة التي كانوا يُسوقون بها
in featuring boys in the commercials, on the boxes,
في ضم الفتيان في الإعلانات التجارية، في الصناديق،
and most of all creating them
والأهم من ذلك كله صنعهم
in less gender-specific colors.
في ألوان أقل ارتباط بالجنس
So this petition started to take off --
لذا بدأ هذا الالتماس بالانتشار
humongously fast, you have no idea.
سريعا بشكل مدهش
I was getting interviewed by all these national news outlets
وحصلت على مقابلات مع جميع هذه المنافذ الإخبارية الوطنية
and press outlets, and it was amazing.
والمنافذ الصحفية، كان مذهلاً.
In three weeks, maybe three and a half,
في ثلاثة أسابيع، وربما ثلاثة ونصف،
I had 46,000 signatures on this petition.
كان لي 46,000 توقيع على هذه العريضة.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Thank you.
شكرا.
So, needless to say, it was crazy.
لذلك، غني عن القول، كان شيئا مجنونا.
Eventually, Hasbro themselves invited me to their headquarters
في نهاية المطاف، هاسبرو أنفسهم دعوني إلى مقرهم
so they could go and unveil
حتي يمكنهم كشف النقاب عن
their new Easy-Bake Oven product to me
فرنهم الجديد للخبز سهل التحضير
in black, silver and blue.
في الأسود والفضي والأزرق.
It was literally one of the best moments of my life.
حرفيا أنها واحدة من أفضل لحظات حياتي.
It was like &amp;quot;Willy Wonka and the Chocolate Factory.&amp;quot;
وكان مثل ويلي ونكا ومصنع الشيكولاتة
That thing was amazing.
وكان هذا الشيء كان مدهشا.
What I didn't realize at the time, however,
ما لم أكن أدركه في ذلك الوقت، ومع ذلك،
was that I had become an activist,
انني كنت قد أصبحت ناشطة،
I could change something,
يمكن أن أغير شيئا،
that even as a kid, or maybe even especially as a kid,
حتى كطفل، أو ربما حتى لا سيما كطفل،
my voice mattered, and your voice matters too.
صوتي مهم، وصوتك أيضا.
I want to let you know it's not going to be easy,
أريد أن أخبركم بأنه لن يكون من السهل،
and it wasn't easy for me,
ولم يكن الأمر سهلاً بالنسبة لي،
because I faced a lot of obstacles.
لأني واجهت الكثير من العقبات.
People online, and sometimes even in real life,
الناس على الإنترنت، وأحيانا حتى في الحياة الحقيقية،
were disrespectful to me and my family,
كانت غير محترمة لي ولعائلتي،
and talked about how the whole thing was a waste of time,
وتحدثوا عن كيف أن كل شيء كان مضيعة للوقت،
and it really discouraged me.
وهذا كان يحبطني.
And actually, I have some examples, because what's better revenge
وفي الواقع، لدى بعض الأمثلة، لأنه ما هو أفضل انتقام
than displaying their idiocy?
من توضيح غباءهم ؟
So, let's see.
لذا، دعونا نرى.
From user name Liquidsore29 --
من اسم المستخدم Liquidsore29-
interesting user names we have here—
أسماء مستخدمين شيقة هنا
&amp;quot;Disgusting liberal moms making their sons gay.&amp;quot;
مثيرة للاشمئزاز الأمهات الليبرالية التي تجعل أبنائهن شواذ
Liquidsore29, really? Really? Okay.
Liquidsore29، حقاً؟ حقاً؟ حسنا.
How about from Whiteboy77AGS:
ماذا عن Whiteboy77AGS:
"People always need something to (female dog) about."
الناس دائماً حاجة شيء إلى (أنثى كلب) حول
From Jeffrey Gutierrez:
من جيفري جوتيريز:
&amp;quot;OMG, shut up. You just want money and attention.&amp;quot;
يا ألهي اخرسي انتي فقط تريدي المال والأهتمام
So it was comments like these
لذا كان مثل هذه التعليقات
that really discouraged me from wanting to make change in the future
حقاً تحبطني وتقلل رغبتي في تغيير المستقبل
because I thought, people don't care,
لأنني اعتقدت، أن الناس لا تهتم
people think it's a waste of time,
الناس يعتقدون أنها مضيعة للوقت،
and people are going to be disrespectful to me and my family.
والناس تتجه لعدم الاحترام لي ولعائلتي.
It hurt me, and it made me think,
أنها تؤذيني وتجعلني أعتقد،
what's the point of making change in the future?
ما هي الفائدة من صنع التغيير في المستقبل؟
But then I started to realize something.
لكن بعد ذلك بدأت أدرك أمر ما
Haters gonna hate.
الحاقدون سيحقدون على أي حال.
Come on, say it with me. One, two, three:
هيا رددها معي 1 2 3
So let your haters hate,
لذا أتركوا حاقديكم يكرهون ما تفعلون
you know what, and make your change,
يمكنك معرفة ذلك وصنع التغيير الخاص بك
because I know you can.
لأنني أعرف أنك تستطيع.
I look out into this crowd,
أنظر إلي هذا الحشد
and I see 400 people
و أرى 400 شخص
who came out because they wanted to know how they could make a change,
الذين جاءوا لأنهم يريدوا معرفة كيفية التغيير
and I know that you can, and all of you watching at home can too
وأنا أعلم أنه يمكنكم، وكل من يشاهد في المنزل يمكنك أيضا
because you have so much that you can do and that you believe in,
لأنك لديك الكثير الذي يمكنك القيام به، وأنا أؤمن،
and you can trade it across all these social media,
أنه يمكنك نشرها عبر هذه الوسائط الاجتماعية،
through Facebook, through Twitter, through YouTube, through Reddit, through Tumblr,
من خلال فيس بوك، تويتر , يوتيوب، ريديت, تمبلر
through whatever else you can think of.
من خلال أي شيء آخر يمكن أن يخطر علي بالك.
And you can make that change.
ويمكن أن تقوم بهذا التغيير.
You can take what you believe in
يمكنك أن تأخذ ما كنت تؤمن به
and turn it into a cause and change it.
وتحويله إلى قضية ويمكنك تغييره.
And that spark that you've been hearing about all day today,
وهذه الفكرة التي نتناقش فيها علي مدار اليوم بأكمله
you can use that spark that you have within you
يمكنك استخدام تلك الفكرة لديك
and turn it into a fire.
وتتحول إلى قضية.
Thank you.
شكرا.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)